This is a look at how DBSCAN works.
我们来看一下 DBSCAN 是如何运作的
DBSCAN stands for density-based spatial clustering of applications with noise.
DBSCAN 指的是具有噪声的基于密度的空间聚类
It grips together points that are closely packed together.
它把那些分布相对密集 距离较近的点聚到一起
In this example, we can see a stark difference from
在这个例子中 我们能体会到
the way that other clustering methods we've seen work.
它和我们之前接触的聚类法有鲜明的差异
That difference is that not every point is part of a cluster.
这个差异就是 不是所有的点都是类的一部分
DBSCAN have labeled these points as noise,
DBSCAN 把这些点标记为噪声
and this shows us the power of DBSCAN in how it can deal with datasets that have noise.
这也说明 DBSCAN 在处理具有噪声的数据集方面作用非常大
Let's look at an example of how DBSCAN works.
我们用个例子来看一下 DBSCAN 是怎么运作的
Let's say we have this dataset.
假如说这是我们要处理的数据集
DBSCAN starts by arbitrarily selecting a point.
DBSCAN 在开始时任意选择一点
Let's say this point here.
我们假定是这个点
So, when we take the point,
我们选定这个点以后
we look in the neighborhood around it,
看一下这个点的邻域
defined by this distance,
所谓的邻域 是由符号 Epsilon 界定的
epsilon, which is one inputs that we pass to DBSCAN.
这个符号是我们输入给 DBSCAN 的
Are there any other points in this neighborhood?
那么 在这个邻域内有其他点吗？
And it turns out that there are none here.
显然没有
So, this point is regarded as a noise point.
所以 这个点就看做是噪声点
It's not part of any cluster.
它不属于任何类
Then we take another point.
我们再选择另外一点
Let's say this point here.
假定是这个点
Let's look at its neighborhood.
我们看一下它的邻域
Are there any other points?
有其他点吗？
Yes, it turns out to be there are two points here,
有 有两个点
including the point that we're looking at.
包括我们选定的那个点
Is that enough to classify as a cluster?
这个数量是否足够我们把它定义为一个类呢？
Well, that's another input,
这就牵扯到另外一个输入了
minimum number of points.
点的最小数量
And so, with this run,
在这个运行过程中
the minimum number of points is five.
点的最小数量是 5
So, we're only two points here,
但我们此处只有两个点 不够五个
not five, and so this point is noise.
所以 这个点也是噪声点
If we do the same thing with this point here,
对这个点也采用相同的分析过程
it would also turn out to be noise because there are
结果显示 它也是个噪声点
no five points around it in its neighborhood.
因为它的邻域内其他点不够五个
Let's look at this point here.
我们来看一下这个点
This is its neighborhood. Are there five points?
这是它的邻域
Well, there are one, two, three, four,
邻域内共有 一、二、三、四 四个点
even if we count these,
即便我们算上这几个点 都只有四个
which they're probably not part of it, that's only four.
这几个点甚至都不在它的邻域内
So, this is also noise.
所以 这也是个噪声点
Things start to become interesting when we look at this central point here.
当我们再看这个中心点的时候 事情就变得有趣了
This is its neighborhood,
这是这个点的邻域
and there are one,
邻域内共有 一、二、三、四、五
two, three, four, five points here. And so, yay!
五个点 耶！
We have found a cluster.
我们找到一个类了
This point is now called a core point,
这个点就叫做核心点
and we've identified our first cluster.
我们也找到了第一个类
Then, we continue to proceed to each point in this cluster,
然后 我们接着逐个分析这个类中的其他点
identifying if they are core points or not.
看看它们是否也是核心点
And then, none of these other points have five in their neighborhoods.
结果发现这些点的邻域中 没有一个是有五个点的
So, while they are part of cluster one,
所以 尽管它们是类一的点
they are regarded all as border points.
它们都被看做是边界点
And so, now we pick another point. Let's say this point here.
现在 我们再来选择一个点 假如说是这个点
Are there five points in its neighborhood?
它的邻域内有五个点吗？
Yes, there are. So, this point is now a core point.
答案是有 所以这个点也是个核心点
We continue to look at the points in its neighborhood.
我们继续看它邻域内的其他点
This one turns out to be a border point.
这个点是边界点
So, it's still part of the cluster,
所以 它是这个类的一部分
but it's not a core point.
但它是个边界点
This one is a core point.
这个点是个核心点
And so, we continue to examine these points,
我们接着看这些点
and this in the end will give us another cluster, cluster two.
这些点组成了另外一个类 即类二
And notice that the shape of cluster two is different.
注意 类二的外形有所不同
So, we can say that cluster one is sort of compact but
所以 我们可以认为类一比较紧凑
closer to continue to be elongated and not necessarily compact.
类二比较狭长 没有那么紧凑
Let's compare DBSCAN to k-means on these benchmark datasets.
我们用这些数据集来对比一下 DBSCAN 和 K-均值聚类法
For the first one,
第一个数据集
DBSCAN gives us this.
DBSCAN 得到的结果是这样
Not terribly useful.
没有多大用
All the points are part of one cluster.
所有的点都属于一个类
For the two crescent dataset however,
但是 双月牙形数据集中
DBSCAN carves them really nicely,
DBSCAN 非常完美的把它们分离开来
and this is all without being handed the number of clusters.
DBSCAN 没有接收到指令 表明它要找到多少个类
So, DBSCAN only gets epsilon and the minimum number of points as its inputs,
它接受的所有指令只有邻域和点的最小数量
not number of clusters.
没有类的数量
And so, the two crescents DBSCAN does a really good job with them.
所以 它在处理双月牙形数据集方面做得非常棒
What about the two rings?
那双环形数据集呢？
Also, good job there.
同样 做的很棒
It carves them out really nicely.
成功的把它们分离出来
With this dataset, the parameters of DBSCAN are probably a little bit aggressive,
这个数据集中 DBSCAN 的参数可能比较大胆
and so these are all noise.
所以 这些点都是噪声点
And then, we have one, two, three,
然后 我们得到了 一、二、三、
four, five, six clusters.
四、五、六 共六个类
The same thing happens here,
这儿也发生了同样的情况
where it found the central masses of the three clusters we're after.
DBSCAN 找到了我们要求的三个类的中心集聚点
But maybe if we change the inputs a little bit,
但如果我们对输入略做改动
it would be able to cleanly separate the three shapes that we would be after here.
它就能非常清楚地把我们要找的三个类分离开来
And with this dataset, it does a really good job just like k-means.
这个数据集 DBSCAN 和 K- 均值聚类法都做的很棒